Samir Pokhrel

Address: Damak-02, Jhapa, Nepal Email:sameerpokharel29@gmail.com

Contact No: +977-9844675101

Portfolio: https://sameerpokhrel-n.github.io/new-portfolio/

Objective:

I am a dedicated software developer with a strong foundation in web development aiming to combine my programming expertise with in-depth data analysis knowledge and committed to furthering my education and expanding my skill set in data analytics.

Work Experience:

Orgware Construct

Full Stack Developer May 2023 - currently working Responsibilities:

- Design and Develop user registration and authentication flows, password recovery mechanisms, integrate 3rd party authentication service (OAuth, Social Logins) and medical coding module.
- Develop a role-based access control system that allowed flexible permissions management and user privilege escalation, resulting in improved data security.
- Integrate the compiled wasm module in application using JavaScript which significantly improves the performance of the application.
- Re-implement the front-end components, ensuring seamless user experience and efficient data management.

Waft Technology

React JS Developer Oct 2022 - Apr 2023

- Responsibilities:
 - Implement View-Model-Data layering architecture for the user interface.
 - Develop SEO friendly user facing e-commerce sites using Next JS.
 - Synchronise Stripe for payment integration with Google cloud services like: firebase for user's subscription, authentication and authorization.
 - Implement CMS on web applications using headless page builder: Prismic.
 - Develop Admin dashboard integrating various modules like: inventory management, point of sales, permission and role-based user management.

Techart Trekkies

React Developer Sep 2021 - Sep 2022 Responsibilities:

- Develop and maintain web applications using React.js and other related technologies.
- Develop Modules like Leave Management, Attendance, Role Management, Payroll System, Class Routine, Post and comment Moderation Modules.
- Manage application state using Redux Duck Patterns and API Integration.

IllionSo Technology

Front-end Developer May 2018 - Aug 2021

Responsibilities:

- Convert UI/UX designs from tools like Figma, Sketch, or Adobe XD into responsive and interactive web pages using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Build prototype for Human Resource Management system(HRMS).
- Ensure the websites function correctly across different browsers (Chrome, Firefox, Safari, Edge) and platforms.

Education:

Bachelors in Electronics and Communication Engineering (BEX)

Kathford International College of Engineering and Management

Percentage: 63.08%

Higher Secondary Boarding School (HSEB)

Damak Model College Percentage: 63.80%

School Leaving Certificate

Mechi Secondary Boarding School

Percentage: 79.88%

English Language Test Score:

IELTS: Overall Band Score: 7

Listening: 7.5Reading: 8Speaking: 6Writing: 6

Technical Skills:

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, PHP, HTML5, CSS3
- Front-end Development: React JS, Angular JS, Next JS
- Back-end Development: Node JS, Express JS
- Web Development: Laravel
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL PostgreSQL
- Data analytics tools and libraries: Tableau, Pandas, NumPy
- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Build Tools: Vite, Webpack, Babel
- Restful APIs: Creation and Integration
- API's Testing Tools: Postman, Hopscotch, Swagger
- Testing Frameworks: Cypress
- Deployment and Hosting: AWS, GCP, Heroku, Netlify
- Project Management Tools and Automation: Jira, Slack, Github actions, Docker, CI/CD Pipelines
- Agile/Scrum Methodologies: Experience working and managing Agile teams.

Key Accomplishment:

- Identified performance optimizations and maintained code quality standards in web applications.
- Developed interactive and responsive web applications using JavaScript, Typescript, HTML and CSS to enhance user experience.
- Proficient in popular JavaScript libraries and frameworks including React JS, Angular and Node JS.
- Demonstrated ability to create and implement custom JavaScript solutions to address specific project requirements.
- Strong understanding of DOM manipulation and asynchronous programming.
- Create secure and efficient RESTful APIs using Express.js.
- Ensure data integrity and security through middleware and validation checks.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams of designers, UI/UX experts, and back-end developers to deliver seamless web applications.
- Understanding the architectural level of applications and gathering requirements.
- Working closely with back-end developers, project managers and stakeholders.

Personal Skills:

- Good communication skills.
- A proactive approach to problem solving.
- Flexible and adaptable to work well individually and with a team.
- Ability to perform under pressure and deliver to challenging time scales.
- Attention to detail.
- Motivated and good learner.

Projects:

Care 2.0

Care 2.0 is the upgraded version of the existing comprehensive web-based medical coding service by <u>Eldberg and Associates</u> and informatics with a key focus on reducing risk and increasing the enterprise value of healthcare providers in the USA.

• Stacks used: React JS, Typescript, Go, PostgreSQL

I/O Fund:

I/O Fund is a top-performing tech portfolio. It runs one of the highest tech-focused stock portfolios in the world to provide serious tech investors with premium services that will give them a competitive edge on growth tech stocks

https://io-fund.com/

• Stacks used: Next JS, React JS, Firebase, Prsimic, Stripe, Mailchimp, WebHooks

Impexo All:

Impexo is a global platform for all the companies involved in logistic operations with integrated tools that help businesses to escalate their efficiency. Impexo provides a simplistic solution for quote requests for the businesses that constantly need to import and export to run their business.

https://allimpexo.com/

• Stacks used: React JS(Class-based Components), Laravel, Redux, SCSS

Waft Commerce:

Waft Commerce is a customizable e-commerce platform to create small to enterprise-level e-commerce applications based on the MERN stack.

https://waftcommerce.com

• Stacks used: React JS, Node JS(Express JS), MongoDB, Tailwind CSS, Redux Toolkit.

References:

Er. Sujit Baniya

CEO, Orgware Construct Pvt. Limited

Contact No: +977-9856034616 Email: <u>s.baniya.np@gmail.com</u>

Mr. Hem Sagar Pokhrel

Founder & Director, illionSo Technologies Pvt. Limited

Contact No: +977-9845006260 Email: sagarpokhrel@illionso.com